A Guide to the Robert Prentiss Daniel Papers 1920-1966
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Robert Printiss Daniel 1920-1966
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
1920-1966
5,000 items
Personal and business correspondence of the fifth President of Virginia State University. Robert P. Daniel was one of the movers in establishing what is now Norfolk State University. He was also very involved in efforts to integrate the institutions of higher learning in Virginia. Acc.#1976-16
Robert Printiss Daniel
Administrative Information
Access
Additional information about Robert P. Daniels may be found in the Virginia State University Archives.
Acquisition Information
A gift from the Daniel Family.
Biographical/Historical Information
Robert P. Daniel was elected to become the fifth president of Virginia State University(then Virginia State College)in December of 1949. He assumed his duties in February of 1950. Mr. Daniel however was not a stranger to Virginia State, having been born on the campus in 1902. This strange twist of fate makes Robert P. Daniel the only President of a state-supported institution who was born on the campus, which he would later serve as chief administrator.
The historical background, which explains, this unusual occurrence lay in the origins of the Daniel Family. The roots of this family began in Louisa County Virginia, with Lucy Langston, Robert Daniel's great great grandmother, who was described as being of African and Virginia Indian origins.
Lucy langston lived as the only wife of Ralph Quarles, a white farmer and landholder in Louisa County. Although this was not a legal union(black-white marriages had been outlawed in Virginia in 1692), the two lived as man and wife for more than thirty years.
From this union came four children: Maria (Daniel's great grandmother), Gideon, Charles and John Mercer Langston (who become the first president of Virginia State in 1886-1887. Ralph Quarles had given his common law wife her freedom earlier and all four of these children were born free between the years of 1800-1829.
Maria Langston married early and her proud father gave her a section of his farm as a wedding gift and also from her father she recieved as her personal property her husband Joseph Powell, who was a slave belonging to Ralph Quarles. Maria Langston like other free blacks, (men and women) around the state of Virginia were forced to hold their husbands and or wives as their personal property in order to keep the family unit together.
From this union came Robert Daniel's grandmother Lucinda, who like her mother also married a slave and was forced to hold him as her enslaved property. Charles Daniel, father of Robert Daniel was born in 1845 in Louisa and until around 1870 lived with his father and learned his trade in shoemaking.
In 1871 he entered the Richmond Institute graduating from the Normal Department in 1877 and its Academic Department in 1878. He studied law for one year at Howard University and then accepted a teaching position in Danville, Virginia.
In 1888 he was invited to become the Secretary of Virginia Normal and Collegiate Institute. It was here in the old Virginia hall that Robert Daniel and all but one of the eight Daniel children were born.
Robert P. Daniel graduated from Virginia Union University in 1924. Later, he obtained his MA and his doctorate at Teachers College. He also completed a post doctoral study in Bible at the Union Theological Seminary in New York during the summers of 1943 and 1946.
Robert Daniel began his career in higher education at Virginia Union University in Richmond as an instructor in mathematics in 1924. Concurrently, Dr. Daniel supervised the establishment of the Norfolk division of Virginia Union University which later became the Norfork division of Virginia State College. He was named president of Shaw University in 1936 until 1950.
Dr. Daniel was elected president of Virginia State College by the State Board of Education on December 15th 1949 following the death of Luther H. Foster.
Dr. Daniel was an active member of several state and national professional organizations.
Scope and Content Information
The Daniel Papers document primarly his becoming the President of Shaw University in 1936 and Virginia State University in 1950. There is also correspondence concerning his activities with a national radio program "Wings over Jordan" and with Alpha Phi Alpha fraternity.In the daniel papers are also some very interesting newsletters printed by the "Political Action Committee" of the Petersburg Improvement Association. These newsletters address the attempts to desegrate public facilities in Petersburg.
Series Description
Series I. Correspondences 1926-1960 Some personal and business correspondence of Robert P. Daniel. Most of the correspondences has to do with Mr. Daniel's leaving Shaw University to become the fifth President of Virginia State College in 1949-1950. sub-series A. Personal Correspondence. sub-series B. Buisness Correspondence
Series II. Organizations and Affiliations Sub-series A. Alpha Phi Alpha Sub-Series B. Virginia Union Alumni Association Sub-Series C. Class (1924)Reunions
Series III. Literary Speeches, Sermons and radio addresses made by Robert P. Daniel from 1936-1966. speeches are arranged by subject and location. Writings State Teachers Report. sub-series A. speeches. sub- series B. Sermons. sub-series C. writings.
Series IV. Photographs. Sub-series A. Personal Sub-series B. The International advisory Board on Liberia Sub-series C. The Alpha Phi Apha Fraternity
Series V. Printed. Sub-Series A. Programs and Flyers with Meetings Attended by Robert Daniel. Sub-Series B. Awards and Certificates Presented by Robert Daniel over a period of years documenting his involvement in a number of organizations. Sub-Series C. Virginia Union University Printed Items generated by Virginia Union University which includes programs, bullitens, and a short history of Virginia Union University. D. Shaw Printed Items such as Bulletins, and other programs E. The Sphinx F.. Degrees and Appointments. Earned degrees for Robert Daniel and members of the Daniel and Taylor Families. Included are appointments for Robert Daniel for several commissions G. Newspapers. Several issues of Black owned newspapers, which were published in North Carolina, Virginia, Massachusetts, and New York. H. Newsclippings. Newsclippings from a number of Newspaper mostly from Virginia I.Civil Rights in Petersburg. Newsletters and Flyers concerning some of the civil rights issues in Petersburg during the 1960's
Series VI. Scrapbooks. Two Scrapbooks, The United States Army Infantry Center and A testimonial in words and music.
Series VII. Artifacts Three Dimensional Items Awarded to or collected by Robert Prentiss Daniel
Contents List
- Correspondence 1926-1960
  - Personal Correspondence
    - John Robert taylor, death of (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Negro Welfare Survey Committee 1929 (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Journal of Negro Education June-August 1942 (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Wing's Over Jordan September 1939 (Box-folder 1:5)
    - Wing's Over Jordan October 1939 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Buisness Correspondence
    - Correspondence- Going to Shaw June 1936 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Correspondence- Going to Shaw July-November 10, 1936 (Box-folder 1:8)
    - Correspondence-Going to Shaw November 12-21 1936 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - Correspondence-Going to Shaw November 23-24, 1936 (Box-folder 1:10)
    - Correspondence-Going to Shaw December 4, 1936 - January 12, 1937 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - Correspondence- Leaving Shaw December 15, 1949 (Box-folder 1:12)
    - Correspondence- Leaving Shaw December 16, 1949 (Box-folder 1:13)
    - Correspondence- Leaving Shaw December 17-19, 1949 (Box-folder 1:14)
    - Correspondence- Leaving Shaw December 18-22, 1949 (Box-folder 1:15)
    - Correspondence- Leaving Shaw December 23-31, 1940 (Box-folder 1:16)
    - Correspondence- Leaving Shaw January 1-9, 1950 (Box-folder 1:17)
    - Correspondence- Leaving Shaw January 10-19, 1950 (Box-folder 1:18)
    - Correspondence- Leaving Shaw January 20-27, 1950 (Box-folder 1:19)
    - Correspondence- Leaving Shaw January 28-31, 1950 (Box-folder 1:20)
    - Correspondence- Leaving Shaw February 1-28, 1950 (Box-folder 1:21)
    - Correspondence- Leaving Shaw March ,1950 (Box-folder 1:22)
    - Correspondence- Leaving Shaw April-October, 1950 (Box-folder 1:23)
    - Correspondence- Leaving Shaw (Box-folder 1:24)
    - Greetings and Congratulations 1950 (Box-folder 1:25)
- Organizations and Affiliations
  - Alpha Phi Alpha
    - Minutes 10th Annual Convention Alpha Phi Alpha 1917 (Box-folder 2:1)
    - Constitution Gamma Chapter (Box-folder 2:2)
    - Minutes Gamma 1909-1910 (Box-folder 2:3)
    - Minutes 1921 (Box-folder 2:4)
    - Report on Budget 1948 (Box-folder 2:5)
    - Budget 1950 (Box-folder 2:6)
    - Treasurer, General Treasurer Alpha Phi Alpha 1949 (Box-folder 2:7)
    - Committee for Budget 1949 (Box-folder 2:8)
    - Budget-V.P. Easter Jurisdiction 1949 (Box-folder 2:9)
    - Correspondence 1907, 1913 (Box-folder 2:10)
    - Correspondence Alpha Phi Alpha 1948-1950 (Box-folder 2:11)
    - Convention Report Alpha Phi Alpha 1949 (Box-folder 2:12)
  - Nu Gamma Chapter, Records
    - Writing- Alpha Phi Alpha (Box-folder 3:1)
    - Minute Book (Gamma Chapter) 1907-1910,1921 (Box-folder 3:2)
    - Minute Book (Gamma Chapter) 1912-1919 (Box-folder 3:3)
    - Minute Book (Gamma Chapter) 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - The Class of 1924 1924
    - Virginia Union Class of 1924 Reunion 1958-1959 (Box-folder 4:4)
    - Virginia Union Class of 1924 Reunion 1960-1961 (Box-folder 4:5)
    - Virginia Union Class of 1924 Reunion 1962, 1964 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Alumni Association
    - Alumni Association March-August 1944 (Box-folder 4:7)
    - Alumni Association April-May 1947 (Box-folder 4:8)
    - Alumni Association February 1949 (Box-folder 4:9)
- Literary
  - Speeches
    - Himself 1950 (Box-folder 5:1)
    - Appraising Your Networth 1952 (Box-folder 5:2)
    - The Challenge of Our Heritage 1953 (Box-folder 5:3)
    - A Place to Stand 1954 (Box-folder 5:4)
    - Father-Son Banquet 1955 (Box-folder 5:5)
    - Presidents Address Vocational Conference 1956 (Box-folder 5:6)
    - Dedication of Tidewater Hall 1957 (Box-folder 5:7)
    - Banquet 1957 (Box-folder 5:8)
    - General Assembly 1958 (Box-folder 5:9)
    - Presidents Address to 1st College Assembly 1958 (Box-folder 5:10)
    - Beginning to 2nd Semester 1959 (Box-folder 5:11)
    - The Challenge of the Heritage of Hampton Institute 1959 (Box-folder 5:12)
    - Statement Presented to Class in Minority Problems 1960 (Box-folder 5:13)
    - College Chapel Assembly 1961 (Box-folder 5:14)
    - Sunday Chapel Program 1962 (Box-folder 5:15)
    - Presidents Address 1963 (Box-folder 5:16)
    - Change & Opportunity in the Tennessee Valley States 1964 (Box-folder 5:17)
    - Christmas Tree Lighting Ceremony 1965 (Box-folder 5:18)
    - CIAA 1966 (Box-folder 5:19)
    - No Title 1936 (Box-folder 5:20)
    - Alpha Phi Alpha 1938 (Box-folder 5:21)
    - No Title 1939 (Box-folder 5:22)
    - Wings Over Jordan July, 24 1939 (Box-folder 5:23)
    - Land Grant Colleges & Universities July, 1 1947 (Box-folder 5:24)
    - Christian Missions and Education 1949 (Box-folder 5:25)
    - Presidents Address December, 15 1949 (Box-folder 5:26)
    - Public Schools and Citizenship (Box-folder 5:27)
    - Deborah, a mother in Isreal (Box-folder 5:28)
    - No Title (Box-folder 5:29)
    - Strengthening Spiritual and Ethical Values (Box-folder 5:30)
    - No Title (Box-folder 5:31)
  - Sermons
    - "Making Your New Year Happy" (Box-folder 6:1)
    - "The Essentials For Progress in The New Year" (Box-folder 6:2)
    - No Title (Box-folder 6:3)
    - "Tomorrow is Yours" (Box-folder 6:4)
    - "The Power of Being With Him" (Box-folder 6:5)
    - "Unhesitating Confidence" (Box-folder 6:6)
    - "The Superior Person" (Box-folder 6:7)
    - :Leadership For Our Times" (Box-folder 6:8)
    - "Baptist Principle and Practice" (Box-folder 6:9)
    - "To Reign is to Rule Over" (Box-folder 6:10)
    - No Title (Box-folder 6:11)
    - No Title (Box-folder 6:12)
    - No Title (Box-folder 6:13)
    - "Quality Education is for Every Man" (Box-folder 6:14)
    - No Title (Box-folder 6:15)
    - No Title (Box-folder 6:16)
    - No Title June, 1956 (Box-folder 6:17)
  - Writings
    - "The Education of the Negro in Virginia" 1926 (Box-folder 6:18)
    - "The Aim of Education" (Box-folder 6:19)
    - Graduate Essay "The New Era" 1920 (Box-folder 6:20)
    - State Teachers Report 1930 (Box-folder 6:21)
    - "A Physiological Delinquent and Non-Delinquent Negro Boys" (Box-folder 6:22)
- Photographs
  - Personal
    - Alpha Phi Alpha 1942 (Box-folder 7:1)
    - Banquet Raleigh 1942 (Box-folder 7:2)
    - Bolling, Francis Mrs. (Box-folder 7:3)
    - Chissell, Robert Dr. (Box-folder 7:4)
    - Claiborne, Mrs (Box-folder 7:5)
    - Daniel, Blanche Mrs. (Box-folder 7:6)
    - Daniel, Blanche Mrs. (Box-folder 7:7)
    - Daniel, Dr (Box-folder 7:8)
    - Daniel and Family (Box-folder 7:9)
    - Daniel, Roberts P. 1938 (Box-folder 7:10)
    - Daniel, Robert P. (Box-folder 7:11)
    - Daniel, Robert P. 1946 (Box-folder 7:12)
    - Daniel Photos (Box-folder 7:13)
    - Walter Daniel (Box-folder 7:14)
    - Davis, Dr & Mrs (Box-folder 7:15)
    - Jones, Cora Z. Mrs. (Box-folder 7:16)
    - Edwards, Namie Miller (Box-folder 7:17)
    - Lindsay, Anna L. (Box-folder 7:18)
    - Unknown Home A.W. Mitchell (Box-folder 7:19)
    - Perry (Box-folder 7:20)
    - Phillips, James T (Box-folder 7:21)
    - Braddus Poindexter (Box-folder 7:22)
    - Ramson, Frances Mrs. (Box-folder 7:23)
    - Scott, Thomas (Box-folder 7:24)
    - Rhunell Ford (Box-folder 7:25)
    - New Farmers of America Banquet 1951 (Box-folder 7:26)
    - R.P. Daniel (Box-folder 7:27)
    - 10th Anniversity Shaw (Box-folder 7:28)
    - Shaw: Commencement (Box-folder 7:29)
    - Simmons, William (Box-folder 7:30)
    - Simmons, William (Box-folder 7:31)
    - Simmons, Mr. and Mrs. William (Box-folder 7:32)
    - Spellman, Robert (Wedding photo) (Box-folder 7:33)
    - Todd (Box-folder 7:34)
    - Unknown (Box-folder 7:35)
    - Unknown (Box-folder 7:36)
    - Va Union University Class Reunion 1944 (Box-folder 7:37)
    - Old Virginia Hall (Box-folder 7:38)
  - The International Advisory Board on Liberia
    - Photo-Liberia (Box-folder 8:1)
    - Photo-Liberia (Box-folder 8:2)
    - Three Million Dollar Hydro-Electric Plant (3000 Kilowatt) (Box-folder 8:3)
    - Cocoa Pods on Young Cocoa Trees. (Box-folder 8:4)
    - Fish Ponds help solveproblem caused by lack of sufficient mineral and protiens in liberian diet (Box-folder 8:5)
    - Team stands before home of Dr. George W. Harley, Famed Metodist Missionary. (Box-folder 8:6)
    - World Health Organization Center at Spain carries out malaria and yaws control projects. (Box-folder 8:7)
    - Highest grade iron ore in world is mined at Bomi Hills by Subsidiary of Republic Steel. (Box-folder 8:8)
    - The evaluation team, with the American Ambassador, confers with President Truman. (Box-folder 8:9)
    - New School building at Salala is typical of several viewed by team throughtout Liberia. (Box-folder 8:10)
    - Where roads ended, the bush trials began. (Box-folder 8:11)
    - After-work class in grade schol subjects is voluntary project of U.S. Technicians at Suakoko (Box-folder 8:12)
    - Bulldozer prepares way for new road through rubber plantation (Box-folder 8:13)
    - Liberian machine stop teacher instructs student while team watches. (Box-folder 8:14)
    - Transportation of all kinds was used by team to cover distant points throughout Liberia. (Box-folder 8:15)
    - Team leaves research building constructed by Liberian Government at Central Experiment Station. (Box-folder 8:16)
    - Photo-Liberia (Box-folder 8:17)
    - Photo-Liberia (Box-folder 8:18)
    - The F.O.A. Evaluation team to Liberia (Box-folder 8:19)
    - Team observes processing of rubbing at main firestone factory. (Box-folder 8:20)
    - Planes are still Novelties in places visited by evaluation team. (Box-folder 9:1)
    - Iron ore at Monrovia Port is loaded for export to U.S.A. and World Markets. (Box-folder 9:2)
    - Country boy frightens away rice birds from new rice fields. (Box-folder 9:3)
    - Tribal markings are still seen today in Liberian Hinterlands. (Box-folder 9:4)
    - President Wilson V.S. Truman of Liberia (Box-folder 9:5)
    - Women in western probince dance a special ceremonial dance to the chief. (Box-folder 9:6)
    - Team visits a small village town to see effects of U.S. Technical Aid. (Box-folder 9:7)
    - Commissioners and Chief were met by team in the central province. (Box-folder 10:1)
    - Gbedin Swamp rice project is inspected by the team after 200-mile motor trip. (Box-folder 10:2)
    - U.S. Ambassador locker and Dr. Daniel Chat with President Truman of Liberia. (Box-folder 10:3)
    - F.O.A. Agriculturist introduces his technical aides to team during visit to Blamata Sub-Station (Box-folder 10:4)
    - Agriculture member of team checks rice at new mill (F.A.O.) near Suakoko. (Box-folder 10:5)
    - U.S. trained Liberian Chemist displays high yielding tomatoes collected during recent F.A.O. leader grant tour of Central and South American Countries. (Box-folder 10:6)
    - Team inspects Boneke Sub-Station near Nyaake in Eastern Liberia. (Box-folder 10:7)
    - Dr. Daniel, Chief of Evaluation Team, Speaks to Maryland County Agriculture Council. (Box-folder 10:8)
    - Surprise 25th anniversary message from Mrs. Daniel is heard at embassy breakfast. (Box-folder 10:9)
    - Maintenance depot in Maryland County will service road building equipment. (Box-folder 10:10)
    - New road building equipment purchased with export bank loan will soon push new road plans. (Box-folder 10:11)
    - Dr. daniel introduces team to the joint commission for economic development. (Box-folder 10:12)
    - Team listens to educational advisor tell of education projects. (Box-folder 10:13)
    - Rice freshly cut from swamp fields (Box-folder 10:14)
    - Dr. Daniel talks with town chiefs about Agricultural and Health Projects in area. (Box-folder 10:15)
  - Alpha Phi Alpha Photographs
    - 19th Annual Convention Richmond, Va Dec 27-31 1926 O.S. (Box-folder 10:16)
    - Convention in Atlanta, Ga O.S. December 31, 1929 O.S. (Box-folder 10:17)
    - Convention in New Orleans December 26, 1929 (Box-folder 10:18)
    - General Convention Tulsa, Oklahoma 1947 O.S. (Box-folder 10:19)
    - 35th Annual Convention
    - 60th Anniversary Convention Saint Louis, Missouri O.S. (Box-folder 10:19)
- Printed
  - Flyers and Programs
    - Supreme Council 330 degree Bulletin 1934 (Box-folder 11:1)
    - Program 52: Annual Session Baptist Sunday School Convention 1936 (Box-folder 11:2)
    - Program: Person County Training School Graduation 1937 (Box-folder 11:3)
    - Program: FAMU May 7, 1939 (Box-folder 11:5)
    - Sunday School and Training Union Convention (Program) July 1944 (Box-folder 11:6)
    - Program 26 Anniversary St. John April 1944 (Box-folder 11:7)
    - Women's Baptist Home-Foriegn Mission Convention 1944 (Box-folder 11:8)
    - General Baptist State Convention Oxford, N.C. 1945 (Box-folder 11:9)
    - Program: Voorhees N & I School May 1945 (Box-folder 11:10)
    - St. Paul's B.C. 1946 (Box-folder 11:11)
    - V.A.E. 1946 (Box-folder 11:12)
    - 5th Annual National YMCA Week Jan 27- February 1, 1957 (Box-folder 11:13)
    - George Washington Carver August 14th, 1965 (Box-folder 11:14)
    - J.E.J. Moore High School Commencement (Box-folder 11:15)
    - Certificate Boyscouts (Box-folder 11:16)
    - The Negro Professional man and the Community (Box-folder 11:17)
    - The Baptist Informer (Box-folder 11:18)
    - Invitations (Box-folder 11:19)
    - The Genesis of Frederick Douglas (Box-folder 11:20)
    - Youth Leadership Institute, the Colored Playground (Box-folder 11:21)
    - Virginia State College (Box-folder 11:22)
    - Langston University Brochure (Box-folder 11:23)
    - Southern Aid Society (Box-folder 11:24)
    - Work with New Students 1921 (Box-folder 11:25)
    - V.A.E. (Box-folder 11:26)
    - Program St. Paul's Baptist Church 1946 (Box-folder 11:27)
  - Awards and Certificates
    - Certificate of Ordination (Box-folder 12:1)
    - The George Washington Carver Endowment Fund Association (Box-folder 12:2)
    - The Association for the study of Negro Life and History (Box-folder 12:3)
    - American Teachers Association (Box-folder 12:4)
    - Citation for Patriotic Devotion (Box-folder 12:5)
    - Eastern Regional Convention of A Phi A (Box-folder 12:6)
    - Iota Sigma Lambda Honorary Society (Box-folder 12:7)
    - Virginia State College Trojan Club (Box-folder 12:8)
    - Alpha Kappa Mu Honor Society Scholarship (Box-folder 12:9)
    - The Frontiers of America (Box-folder 12:10)
    - Imperial Council (Box-folder 12:11)
    - National Society of Scabbard and Blade (Box-folder 12:12)
    - Kappa Phi Kappa (Box-folder 12:13)
    - The National Society of Scabbard and Blade (Box-folder 12:14)
    - Kappa Mu Epsilon (Box-folder 12:15)
    - U.S. Civil Service Commission (Box-folder 12:16)
    - Commonwealth of Virginia (Box-folder 12:17)
    - Distinguish Service Award (Box-folder 12:18)
    - Commonwealth of Virginia (Box-folder 12:19)
    - Commonwealth of Virginia (Box-folder 12:20)
    - The Poultry and Egg National Board (Box-folder 12:21)
    - Member of the Board Control for Southern Regional Education (Box-folder 12:22)
    - Commission on Higher Education (Box-folder 12:24)
    - Certificate of Appreciation (Box-folder 12:25)
    - Commonwealth of Virginia (Box-folder 12:26)
    - National Education Association (Box-folder 12:27)
    - Commonwealth of Virginia (Box-folder 12:28)
    - Department of Defense (Box-folder 12:29)
    - Hermy Carter Dancing School (Box-folder 12:30)
    - National Society of Pershing Rifles (Box-folder 12:31)
    - Award for thirteen years of service (Box-folder 12:32)
    - The Sigma delta Psi Honarary Athletic Fraternity April 30, 1959 (Box-folder 12:33)
    - Sigma Pi Phi Fraternity August 12, 1948 (Box-folder 12:34)
    - Nineteenth Biennial convocation Sigma Pi Phi Fraternity August 11, 1948 (Box-folder 12:36)
    - Pi Omega Pi National Business Education Fraternity (Box-folder 12:37)
    - Alpha Mu Gamma National Honarary foriegn Language Fraternity (Box-folder 12:38)
    - Sigma Delta Psi March 9, 1959 (Box-folder 12:39)
    - Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity April 22, 1921 (Box-folder 12:40)
    - The American Baptist Home Mission Society Teacher's Commission October 15, 1923 (Box-folder 12:41)
    - Kappa Delta Pi Honor Society in Education May 11, 1959 (Box-folder 12:42)
  - Virginia Union University
    - Virginia Union University What It Signifies T.J. Morgan LL.D (Box-folder 13:1)
    - Virginia Union University 1924 Commencement 1924 (Box-folder 13:2)
    - Virginia Union University Eucational Club (Box-folder 13:3)
    - Virginia Union University Educational Club 1930-1931 (Box-folder 13:4)
    - Virginia Union University Educational Club 1931-1932 (Box-folder 13:5)
    - Virginia Union University Educational Club 1932-33 (Box-folder 13:6)
    - Alumni Banquet Program June 7, 1948 (Box-folder 13:7)
    - Alumni Banquet Program H.B. Hucles June 6, 1949 (Box-folder 13:8)
    - Howard vs. Union May 2, 1924 (Box-folder 13:9)
    - Classes Day Exercises June 4, 1924 (Box-folder 13:10)
    - Union Hartshorn Bulletin February, 1925 (Box-folder 13:11)
    - Union Hartshorn Bulletin January, 1928 (Box-folder 13:12)
    - Virginia Union University Bulletin February, 1929 (Box-folder 13:13)
    - Virginia Union University Bulletin February, 1930 (Box-folder 13:14)